Guide to the Miscellaneous Personal Papers Collection
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Individuals A-L, Series I
  - Dinsmore, Charles Allen
    - Writings and notes: Includes an article written by Dinsmore, "The Moral System of Dante's Inferno, newspaper clippings of book reviews, and notes (Box 97)
  - Dirks, J. Edward
    1940 - B.A., Dubuque; 1943 - B.D., YDS; 1947 - Ph.D., Columbia; 1955-1958 - Associate Professor Religion in Higher Education, Yale Divinity School; 1958-1967 - Stephen Merrell Clement Professor of Christian Methods, YDS; 1967-1968 - Research Consultant, YDS.
    - Addresses, Lectures, and Papers: Writings related to religion in higher education. Sample titles: "The Religious Dimension in Education", "The Community of Faith and the Community of Learning", and "A Theology of the Campus Christian Ministry" given at the Danforth Conference for Campus Christian Workers. Dirks' licensure and ordination lecture, "Justification by Faith", is included., 1952-1967, n.d. (Box 321, Folder 1-16)
    - Yale Divinity School: Danforth Program: The Danforth Study of Campus Ministries, sponsored by the Danforth Foundation beginning in 1963, was directed by Kenneth Underwood, a YDS colleague of Dirks. The project documented the state of religious awareness and commitment on American university and college campuses. (Box 321, Folder 17-18)
    - Travel Diary: Documents Dirks' travels from February through June of 1957, in India, Asia, and the Middle East. Entries are primarily reflections on the various discussions Dirks had with professors, students, administrators, and church leaders concerning universities and higher education in general within these countries. (Box 321, Folder 19)
    - Shorter Publications: A variety of different theological publications containing articles written by and about Dirks. Sample titles: "Commemoration Day Address: 1964" and "The Pursuit of Learning to the Glory of God" in the Wesleyan Studies in Religion., 1957-1964 (Box 322, Folder 20-21)
    - Sermons written by Dirks. Many of these sermons appear to be given within academic setting. Several were given at Yale Divinity School, 1957, 1960, 1963 - 1965, n.d. (Box 322, Folder 22-24)
    - One letter between the Office of the Dean at Yale Divinity School and Dirks, 1958 Apr (Box 322, Folder 25)
    - Longer Publications: Introductions, chapters, and drafts of books written by Dirks. Sample titles: "The Contemporary University World: Freedom and Responsibility in the Higher Learning of Today", "Impressions of Christian Colleges in Asia", and "The Christian Community at Study: (chapter I) A Theology of Knowledge for the Christian Educational Community". (Box 322, Folder 26-30)
  - Dougall, William
    683 - Born in Scotland Educated at the University of Glasgow; 1707 - Licensed, Presbytery of Dunblane; 1710 - Ordained to Birnie, Presbytery of Elgin; 1716 - Married Katherine King; 1766 -Died.
    - Bound manuscript volume. Appears to be an index to an unidentified work preceded by a bibliography of works listed by author, 1710 (Box 270)
  - Downey, William Scott
    Rev. Downey was the author of Proverbs, which was printed in many editions in beginning in 1851.
    - Handwritten manuscript, "The Youthful Days and Adventures of the Celebrated Dr. Dick Buckles of Bucklesville" (300 pp.), 1870 (Box 422, Folder 2)
  - Dowsley, Andrew
    Dowsley was a Church of Scotland missionary in Madras, India.
    - Seven A.L.S. from Andrew Dowsley in Madras to his brother, Kennedy Dowsley. One A.L.S. from Jennie (Mrs. Andrew Dowsley) to Juliette (Mrs. Kennedy Dowsley). Typewritten transcripts of all, 1877-1878 (Box 329, Folder 8)
  - Dudley, Raymond Augur
    1890 -Born in Guilford, CT; 1916 -B. A., Yale College, became involved with Student Volunteer Movement; 1915-1917 - Served with YMCA during Mexican War; 1918-1919 - U.S. Army; 1918 -Married Katherine Ellen Clark; eventually had four children; 1919 -B.D., Yale Divinity School; 1919 - Ordained at Congregational Church in Guilford; 1919-1943 - served American Madura Mission of the American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions, in South India, stationed in Tirumangalam and Aruppukottai; 1937 -M.A., Kennedy School of Missions, Hartford, CT; 1944-1957 - Secretary to India for ABCFM; 1954 - Honorary Doctor of Laws, Olivet College, Olivet, MI; 1957 - Assigned to Geneva to work with World Council of Churches; traveled widely; 1971 -Retired in Salem, Oregon.
    - Circular letters describing RAD's work in India, 1922-1930 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Circular letters describing RAD's work in India, 1932-1938 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Autobiography of RAD, 1977 Jan (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Master's thesis: "Voluntary service", 1937 May (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Report re. Weltmissions Konferenz in Willingen, 1952 Jul (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Talks and sermons, 1937-1954 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Scripture verses (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Notes from reading; miscellaneous notes (Box 2, Folder 8-9)
    - Collected material: Jokes and poems (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Collected material: Constitution of Church of North India including Faith and Order of the Church, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Church members manual (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Photographs illustrating Christian work in India: Indian occupations (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Photographs illustrating Christian work in India: education (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Photographs illustrating Christian work in India: evangelism (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Photographs illustrating Christian work in India: medical work (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Photographs illustrating Christian work in India: famine (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Photographs illustrating Christian work in India: miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Photographs illustrating Christian work in India: RAD in groups (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Slides of ABCFM mission in India and Indian occupations (Box Ov1)
    - Photo of Student Volunteer Group, 1914 (Box Ov1)
    - Photo of Northfield Student Volunteer convention, 1912 (Box Ov1)
    - Photo of YMCA/ Dwight Hall group at Yale, 1917 (Box Ov1)
    - Photo of Beta delegation, class of 1916 (Box Ov1)
    - Copy of letter from Samuel W. Dudley to ABCFM recommending Mary A. Brainerd for missionary service; copy of letter from Mary Brainerd Ives to Mary Norton of North Guilford, CT written on board ship en route to missionary service in Hawaii, 1836 (Box 333, Folder 10)
  - Eady, Constance Swinfen
    Eady was an Assemblies of God missionary in South India.
    - 4 circular letters from Eady, written from Bangalore, describe mission work with news from village churches, work with outcastes and Moslems., 1940-1943 (Box 456, Folder 10)
  - Eddy family
    George Washington Eddy (1811-1897) was an inventor of printer's ink. He and his wife, had communications with Presbyterian missionaries in Siam (Thailand) Mary Mattoon (wife of Stephen Mattoon) and Samuel R. and Henrietta House. The Houses were neighbors of the Eddys in upstate New York. Eddy also received letters and gifts from Chau Fa Mongkut, Crown Prince of Siam, who later became King and was popularized in the book "Anna and the King of Siam."
    - Letters of Mary Mattoon to Mrs. George Washington Eddy, 1848, n.d. (Box 335, Folder 7)
    - Letters of Samuel and Henrietta House to Mrs. G. W. Eddy, 1847, 1860, 1862 (Box 335, Folder 8)
    - Transcripts of letters from Chau Fa Mongkut to Mrs. and Mrs. G. W. Eddy; copies of gift cards from Mongkut, 1847, 1849, n.d. (Box 335, Folder 9)
    - Article in Boston Evening Transcript re. G.W. Eddy's communications with Chau Fa Mongkut. Articles in The Eddy Family Association Bulletin by Roberta Clark (great granddaughter of G.W.Eddy) re. the Eddy - Siam connection, 1931, 1977-1979 (Box 335, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence between Roberta Clark and Abbot Low Moffat, author of Mongkut, the King of Siam; collected material re. other Eddy family members, 1962-1979 (Box 335, Folder 11)
  - Edwards, Jonathan
    Jonathan Edwards (October 5, 1703 – March 22, 1758) was an preacher, philosopher, and Congregationalist Protestant theologian. The primary collection of Edwards papers at Yale is in the Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library.
    - Transcripts of sermon manuscripts of Jonathan Edwards prepared by Bonita and Edwin Burtner, 1730-1751 (Box 267)
  - Eells Family
    Nathaniel Eells of Scituate, MA, was born in 1677, graduated from Harvard in 1699, and died in 1750. His sons included Samuel Eells (b. 1706 ), Nathaniel (b. 1711; pastor of the Congregational Church in Stonington, CT), and Edward (b. 1713; pastor of the Congregational Church in Middletown, CT ). James Eells, son of Edward, was born 1742/43 and licensed to preach in Glastonbury, CT in 1769; Earnest E. Eells, a later descendant, was a chaplain in the U.S. Navy.
    - Bound volume of manuscript notes for sermons by Nathaniel Eells (b. 1677), 1705-1709 (Box 330, Folder 1)
    - Bound ms. "Articles of Fidei" by Samuel Eells, 1767 (Box 330, Folder 2)
    - Typescript: "Some Unpublished Facts about Dartmouth College, the Revolution, and Yale: the Letters of Two Brothers, Rev. Nathaniel Eells and Edward Eells" Transcription of letters written in 1748, the originals of which were destroyed because regarded as dangerously conspiratorial by the authors (Box 330, Folder 3)
    - Ms. sermon of James Eells, first preached in Branford, CT, 1785 (Box 330, Folder 4)
    - Unidentified ms. sermon (possibly James Eells), n.d. (Box 330, Folder 4)
    - Typescript unpublished manuscript by Earnest E. Eells: "The "colonization" of Liberia and the United States Navy at war with the slave-trader-pirates on the west coast of Africa: a narrative based on original journals, letters and ship logs" (728 pp) (Box 330, Folder 5-6)
    - Correspondence, notes, and drafts related to Earnest E. Eells' manuscript on Liberia, 1972, n.d. (Box 331, Folder 1)
    - Printed material collected in connections with E. E. Eells' ms. on Liberia, re. slavery, piracy, and U.S. Navy, 1875-1968 (Box 331, Folder 2)
    - Typescript transcription of journal of the Rev. John Christian Wiltberger, agent of the American Colonization Society in Liberia (1820-1822); transcribed by E. E. Eells in 1969 from original in Library of Congress (418 pp. and appendices); Prayer book with notes owned by Rev. Christian Wiltberger (Box 331, Folder 3-4)
    - Typescript unpublished manuscript by Earnest E. Eells: "Theophilus Chamberlain" re. Sandeman loyalists and blacks who emigrated from Nova Scotia to Sierra Leone and Liberia (pp. 1-253), 1980 (Box 331, Folder 5)
    - Typescript unpublished manuscript by Earnest E. Eells: "Theophilus Chamberlain" re. Sandeman loyalists and blacks who emigrated from Nova Scotia to Sierra Leone and Liberia (pp. 248-396 and appendices), 1980 (Box 332, Folder 1-3)
  - Elliott, Arthur James
    "Dad" A.J.Elliott (1875-1952) served the YMCA Student Division from 1907 to 1951. During the last sixteen years he was executive secretary of Christian evangelism among youth and led the student conferences held at Lake Geneva. Elliott traveled to Japan, China, and the Philippines in 1925 on behalf of the Student YMCA. In 1935 he was sent on a similar mission around the world. For additional biographical information see pamphlet Touchdowns for the Lord in the library's cataloged collection. See additional A.J. Elliott correspondence in Record Group No. 58, YMCA Student Division Archives.
    - Obituary, photograph of A.J. Elliott. (Box 410, Folder 1)
    - 8 mm. films taken during Elliott's travels. The films include views of the countries visited, Elliott and his wife Otillia, etc: 1) China: scenes of harbor, boats, streets, countryside, children, temple; 2) Japan: boats, people, pagoda, dancers, rickshaw, countryside, Japanese home; 3) Germany and Switzerland: railroad stations, Olympic Stadium in Berlin, parade of athletes, towns, League of Nations building; 4) Italy: Venice, lacemakers, streets, Rome, etc.; 5) Jerusalem and Egypt: pyramids, desert, camel riding, Wailing Wall, holy sites; 6-8) Russia / Soviet Union: school, stadium, folkdances, workers, military, parade, Stalin, Metro subway system, buildings, shrines, statues,Youth camp, harvesting; 9) Norway: scenes at sea, harbor, dancers, fjords, countryside; 10) In U.S.?: people in snow, airplane taking off, gardens, ca. 1935-1937 (Box 410, Folder 2)
    - 8 mm. films taken during Elliott's travels. The films include views of the countries visited, Elliott and his wife Otillia, etc: 1-2) India: tea at Maharah, school, lepers, Delhi, Agra, wealthy Indian family, Hindu temple, street scenes, Lahore; 3) Grand Canyon; 4) Yellowstone, ca. 1935-1937 (Box 411, Folder 1)
  - Elliott, Edna
    Edna Elliott was a teacher at Methodist Boy's School in Malaya from 1919 to 1921. She later taught school in the Pittsburgh area.
    - Letters to family from Malaya, 1919 Aug - 1921 Apr (Box 327, Folder 1)
    - Letter fragments, 1921 May, n.d. (Box 327, Folder 2)
    - Letters of others, incl. Chiong Su-Inn, 1920 Jan - 1926 Jun (Box 327, Folder 3)
    - Programs from events, n.d. (Box 327, Folder 4)
    - Photographs of groups, individuals, scenery in Malaya, ca. 1919-1921 (Box 327, Folder 5)
    - Photograph album - Malaya, unidentified, ca. 1919-1921 (Box 327, Folder 6)
    - Photograph album belonging to Carrie Kenyon - Malaya, ca. 1919-1921 (Box 327, Folder 7)
    - Messages in Chinese from school parents, n.d. (Box 327, Folder 8)
    - Newsletters: "Working for Malaya's Salvation", 1929 Jul - Nov (Box 327, Folder 9)
    - Unidentified blockprints (Box 327, Folder 10)
    - Minutes of the Malaya Woman's Conference (Methodist Episcopal Church), 1927, 1930, 1931, 1933, 1934, 1937, 1939 (Box 327, Folder 11-13)
    - Malaysia Annual Conference, 1905 (Box 327, Folder 14)
    - Minutes of the Malaya Conference (Methodist Episcopal Church), 1925, 1930, 1931 (Box 327, Folder 15-16)
    - Newsclippings, incl. re. Elliott, historic site in Malacca, n.d. (Box 327, Folder 17)
  - Ellis, Harrison W.
    Ellis (d. 1870) was an American Presbyterian missionary in Liberia, arriving in Monrovia in 1847.
    - Handwritten letter from Ellis in Monrovia to Walter Lowrie, Secretary of the Board of Foreign Missions of the Presbyterian Church, U.S.A., 1850 March 18 (Box 53, Folder 8)
  - Emmons, Nathanael
    1745 - Born in East Haddam, CT; 1767 - Graduated from Yale College; 1773-1827 - Ordained and served church in Wrentham, MA; 1798 - D.D., Dartmouth; 1840 - Died.
    - Two manuscript sermons, 1810 Jun, Dec (Box 213)
  - Erkens, Gerard
    - Contents of album compiled by Erkens, including correspondence, memorials to other Catholic missionaries in Indonesia (such as Jef Henderyck) and other material documenting CICM mission work in Sulawesi (Toraja), Indonesia, 1979-2000 (Box 439, Folder 1-4)
    - Photo album - people and scenes in Indonesia (Box 439, Folder 5)
    - Photo Album A: "Reis Naar Indonesie" G. Erkens, 1997 (Box 439, Folder 6-7)
    - Photo Album B: "Reis Naar Indonesie" G. Erkens, 1997 (Box 440, Folder 1-2)
  - Evans, Elizabeth Margaret
    Evans was an American Presbyterian missionary to Japan from 1911 to 1951 where she taught at the Hokusei Jo Gakko mission school.
    - Photographs: portraits of Evans, Evans with Japanese colleagues, alumni of Hokusei Jo Gakko, "Warrior assembly" performance at 30th anniversary of Hokusei Jo Gakko, people in boat, hotel at Norboribetsu, no date (Box 456, Folder 11)
  - Evans, Sara M.
    Professor of history, University of Minnesota; editor of "Journeys that opened up the world: women, student Christian movements, and social justice, 1955-1975" published by Rutgers University Press, 2003.
    - 22 audio-cassette recordings of interviews that inaugurated project leading to publication of Journeys that opened up the world" (Box 383)
  - Everett, Edward Irving
    Everett was an American Methodist missionary to the Congo.
    - Letter from Everett to a Methodist church in the U.S. describes life in Congo and mission school and requests donations, 1946 (Box 456, Folder 12)
  - Fenn, Stephen
    Fenn graduated from Yale Divinity School in 1854.
    - Bound notebook of handwritten lecture notes taken during Fenn's time at Yale Divinity School, 1853 (Box 42, Folder 2)
      Includes notes on lectures by Nathaniel William Taylor and George Park Fisher.
  - Fernando, Peter
    Fr. Fernando was a missionary parish priest in the diocese of Vellore, based in Arni, Tamil Nadu, South India.
    - Letter from Fernando request donations to establish social welfare centers in the region, 1972 (Box 456, Folder 13)
  - Ferris, Theodore Parker
    1908 - Born in Port Chester, NY; 1929 - A.B., Harvard; 1931 - B.D., General Theological Seminary, NY; ordained into the Episcopal ministry; 1933-37 - Assistant minister, Grace Church, NYC; tutor, General Theological Seminary; 1937-42 - Rector, Emmanuel Church Baltimore; 1942-72 - Rector, Trinity Church, Boston; 1943-64 - Instructor in homiletics, Episcopal Theological Seminary, Cambridge; 1961 - S.T.D., General Theological Seminary
    - Printed sermons preached at Trinity Church, Boston, 1946-1972 (Box 265–266)
  - Finger, Harold J.
    Fingers was a missionary of the Churches of Christ in Australia who worked in New Hebrides (Vanuatu) for 15 years and then in New Guinea.
    - Untitled typescript ms. re. mission work in New Hebrides in the 1940s-1950s, n.d. (Box 329, Folder 9)
  - Fisher, George Park
    1827 - Born; 1847 - B.A., Brown University; 1850 - M.A., Brown University; 1851 - B.D., Andover Theological Seminary; 1854-1861 - Livingston Professor of Divinity, Yale; 1861-1878 - Professor of Ecclesiastical History, Yale; 1866 - D.D., Brown University; 1867 - M.A. (hon.), Yale; 1878-1901 - Titus Street Professor of Ecclesiastical History, Yale; 1879 - LL.D., Princeton University; 1886 - D.D., University of Edinburgh; - S.T.D., Harvard University; 1895-1901 - Dean of Yale Divinity School; 1896 - D.D., Princeton University; 1901 - LL.D., Yale; 1901-1909 - Professor Emeritus;1909 - Died.
    - Correspondence: All letters are addressed to Fisher, except one from Fisher to Dean Sanders of the Divinity School. Letters are mostly regarding writings and professional matters. Correspondents include: Horace Bushnell, John Brown, Robert William Dale, Theodore Dwight Woolsey, Charles William Eliot, James Bryce, Mark Hopkins, James McCosh, Edward Amasa Parks, 1869-1923, n. d. (Box 122)
    - Handwritten diary: "A Record of Student Days in Germany": journal type diary including data on Germany during this period, and daily events in the life of a theological student in Hanover., 1852-1853 (Box 114)
    - Printed articles and sermons; list of writings located in first folder., 1857-1899 (Box 114)
    - Publisher contracts: Fifteen contracts for Fisher's books, 1877-1903 (Box 114)
    - Diplomas (Box Ov1)
    - Copies of letters to GPF incl. from Ralph Waldo Emerson, Sarah Orne Jewett, Oliver Wendell Holmes, Julius Seelye, Francis Parkman, Henry Van Dyke, Timothy Dwight; introductions by William and Elinor Newbold explaining provenance of the letters, 1866-1900 (Box 333, Folder 11)
  - Fosdick, Harrison
    1862 - Born in Bethlehem, CT; 1890-1894 - Yale Divinity School; 1893 - B.D. YDS; 1896 - Ordained at Congregational Church in Bethlehem, CT; 1896-1935 - Served various churches in CT and MA; 1940 - Died.
    - Photographs and journals, inc. 1893 YDS class photo, commemorative pin from Yale bicentennial (1901), 1893, 1901, n.d. (Box 325)
  - Foster, Mary E.
    Foster was 5th great grand-daughter of Jonathan Edwards.
    - Typescript autobiographica/philosophical writings by Foster, 1996 (Box 384, Folder 9)
  - Found, Norman
    Found was a Methodist medical missionary in Korea 1921-1930s, Professor of Internal Medicine, Severance Union Medical College, Seoul.
    - Letters to/from Norman Found, incl. re. Severance Union Medical College, mission work in Korea, 1929-1970, n.d. (Box 329, Folder 10-11)
    - Article by Found: "Morbidity Among Koreans Living in the Seoul Area", 1932 (Box 329, Folder 12)
    - Material re. Severance Union Medical College, 1930-1934, n.d. (Box 329, Folder 13)
    - Material re. Ewha College, 1939 (Box 329, Folder 14)
    - Collected material re. missionaries and mission work in Korea, 1932-1968, n.d. (Box 329, Folder 15)
  - Frazier, Elizabeth H. and Donald H.
    Donald Frazier and Elizabeth Frazier graduated from Yale Divinity School in 1938 and 1940 respectively. They remained active in YDS affairs, including serving as class agents.
    - Correspondence and documents related to Yale Divinity School, 1973-1986 (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence and documents related to Yale Divinity School, 1987-1988 (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence and documents related to Yale Divinity School, 1989-1990 (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence and documents related to Yale Divinity School, 1991-1993 (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence and documents related to Yale Divinity School, 1994-1995 (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence and documents related to Yale Divinity School, 1996-1998, no date (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - Compiled set of documents related to the Yale Divinity School "Save the Quad" movement, 1996-1998 (Box 46, Folder 7-8)
    - Sampling of family correspondence, 1958-1964 (Box 46, Folder 9)
    - Sampling of personal correspondence, 1948-1988 (Box 46, Folder 10)
    - Collected documents related to women's issues, 1963-1991 (Box 46, Folder 11)
    - Memorabilia, including program for Elizabeth Frazier's ordination, 1962, no date (Box 46, Folder 12)
  - Freeman, Nathaniel
    1778 - Born; 1805 - Graduated from Yale College; 1811-14 - Ordained, served church in Oxford, CT; 1819-32 - Served church in Easton, CT; 1833-42 - Served church in Fairfield, CT; 1854 - Died.
    - One manuscript sermon, n.d. (Box 212)
  - Froeberg, Peter
    Froeberg was Pastor of the Swedish Evangelical Lutheran Salem Church, Bridgeport, CT and President of Upsala College, Kenilworth, NJ 1910-1920.
    - Holograph sermons / talks in English incl. re. Lutheran Church, n.d. (Box 329, Folder 16)
    - Holograph sermons / talks in Swedish incl. re. Lutheran Church, n.d. (Box 329, Folder 17)
    - Typescript sermons / talks, n.d. (Box 329, Folder 18)
    - Commencement program and Baccalaureate sermon, Upsala College, 1914 (Box 329, Folder 19)
  - Frost, Caroline
    1870 Jan 3 - Born in Hollis, New Hampshire; 1892-1893 - Taught at Peabody Academy, Troy, North Carolina; 1894 - Graduated from Mount Holyoke College; Taught at:1894-1897 - Talladega College; 1897-1900 - Huguenot Seminary, Cape Colony, South Africa; 1900-1909 - Umzumbe Home, serving under the American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions; 1909-1940 - Adams College, M.S., Natal (ABCFM); 1941 - Retired; 1945 - Died in Waltham, Massachusetts. This collection complements the papers of John A. Reuling (YDSL RG No. 30). Reuling was director of teachers' training at Adams College from 1927 to 1941.
    - Correspondence related to Allison Champion, a student of CEF at Adams College who went on to become a pioneer African labor leader in S. Africa, 1913-1937 (Box 302, Folder 1)
    - Note to George Champion from Martha Lindley, 1905 (Box 302, Folder 2)
    - Fragmentary note from N.A. Luthuli, n.d. (Box 302, Folder 3)
    - Letters on the occasion of CEF's retirement: from Edgar Brookes, from Dora Cele, from staff of Adams Church (in Zulu), 1940 (Box 302, Folder 4)
    - Diaries: two volumes with daily entries, 1931, 1932 (Box 302, Folder 5)
    - Autograph books: two volumes containing messages from colleagues and friends, 1900-1940 (Box 302, Folder 6)
    - Photograph albums: three volumes containing photos of colleagues, Adams College, native South Africans, scenery, etc., 1910-1925 (Box 302, Folder 7-8)
    - Photographic negatives, 1929-1936, n.d. (Box 302, Folder 9)